

Berlin/Germany

□ (+49) 176 76494837 | ■ utku@turunc.me | 🛣 utku.turunc.me | 🖫 utkuturunc | 🛅 utkuturunc

Summary_

Full Stack Software Engineer of 8 years with system design and leading experience, entrepreneur, freelancer.

While I prefer working with TypeScript, NextJS, React, and PostegreSQL, I have experience with many other technologies and languages, including Python, Scala and Kotlin.

Work Experience

Lit Growth Partners Berlin, Germany

Co-Founder - Software Engineer Feb. 2023 - Now

• Started a team for providing product lead growth services.

- Currently working with TaxFix to implement and optimize growth levers.

Freelance Software Engineer Berlin, Germany

FULL STACK

Jan. 2023 - Now

• Providing full stack development for multiple clients.

• A wellness app, an advertising platform, a real-estate management platform

Notionlayer.com Berlin, Germany

FOUNDER Aug. 2022 - Now

• Created Notionlayer, a SaaS for building websites out of Notion.

Entrepreneur First Berlin, Germany

Entrepreneur in Residence Apr. 2022 - Jul. 2022

• Worked on customer discovery for multiple business ideas.

Created a factory simulation app, based in React.

_blaenk Gmbh Berlin, Germany

SOFTWARE ENGINEER May. 2021 - Apr. 2022

· Implemented kubernetes cluster.

- Designed the backend and the frontend architecture with the team.
- Created a data warehouse and a social shopping app.

Zalando SE Berlin, Germany

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Feb. 2019 - Apr. 2021

- Designed and built a printing system architecture in microservices.
- Worked with Scala and Kotlin to develop logistics applications.

McMakler GmbH.

Berlin, Germany

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Aug. 2018 - Feb. 2019

• Worked as a NodeJS backend engineer for in house CRM system.

Valensas Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jul. 2016 - Jul. 2018

- Lead small to medium sized projects, managing communications with product and engineering teams of customers.
- Worked for a large scale banking project, designing and developing microservices
- · Designed a chatbot framework that integrate with other web services and use machine learning and natural language processing.

Freelance Software Engineer

Istanbul, Turkey

FULL STACK - PART TIME

Jan. 2013 - May 2021

- Offered services that cover the entire product pipeline, including design, management, implementation, infrastructure and deployment of projects.
- Designed and developed: a directory of blogs webpage, truck rental and route planning app, motorcycle renting and tour reservation app, college book sharing app, donation page for a non-profit, chat based party game, online realtime fitness app.

Skills

Languages Typescript, JavaScript, Python, Kotlin, Scala

Technologies ReactJS, React Native, NextJS, NodeJS, GraphQL, Express, Flask, Fastify, Ktor, HTML5, CSS, REST

DevOPS AWS, Google Cloud Engine, Docker, Terraform, Kubernetes, Linux, Microservices

Database Redis, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Firestore

Presentations

Turkey Artificial Intelligence Initiative (turkiye.ai)

Istanbul, Turkey

PRESENTER FOR VALENSAS

Oct. 2017

• A talk about the usage of artificial intelligence in our projects

Education

Boğaziçi University

Istanbul, Turkey Sep. 2012 - Jun. 2016

B.S. IN ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING

• Completed electronics specialization

Projects

Wellness App Berlin, Germany

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - GUT FEELING • Full-stack design and development of a wellness app, using NextJS and React Native Jan. 2023 - Feb. 2023

Factory Simulation Software

Berlin, Germany

CO-FOUNDER -May. 2022 - Aug. 2022

• Development of a React based factory simulation software, using NextJS

Social Shopping App

Berlin, Germany

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - _BLAENK GMBH.

May. 2021 - Apr. 2022

• Full-stack design and development of a social shopping app, using Kotlin and React Native

Logistics Printing System

Berlin, Germany

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - ZALANDO SE

Feb. 2019 - Apr. 2021

• Design and development of a large scale printing solution for logistics

Tosla - P2P Banking Application by Akbank

Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - VALENSAS

Feb. 2018 - Jul. 2018

- · Developed several microservices, namely core banking and social feeds for a modern peer to peer banking application
- Set up Kubernetes configurations and deployment pipelines.
- Project uses Spring Boot and Hibernate for core banking, Scala (Akka) for social feeds

Akbank Assistant - Akbank Chatbot

Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - VALENSAS

Sep. 2017 - May. 2018

- Developed a chatbot for Akbank which can be used to transfer money and pay invoices, one of the largest banks in Turkey.
- Tech stack: TypeScript, Scala, and Akbank datacenters on Linux.
- Project has been released with a TV commercial and printed press coverage.

Boti - Turkish Airlines Chatbot

Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - VALENSAS

Feb. 2017 - Sep. 2017

- Developed a chatbot for Turkish Airlines. The bot can be used to buy tickets, select seats, check-in, query flight statuses and more.
- · Tech stack: TypeScript, Scala, and AWS.

Hepsichat - Hepsiburada Chatbot

Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - VALENSAS

Nov. 2016 - Feb. 2017

- Developed a customer support chatbot for the largest e-commerce platform in Turkey, Hepsiburada.
- · The chatbot greets users, collects information and solves specific issues, if it cannot resolve the issue it redirects the users to human agents, saving time and resources.
- · Tech stack: TypeScript, Scala, and AWS.